Leroy Y. Beaujon Railroad Collection 1997.0042
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Leroy Y. Beaujon Railroad Collection
undated, 1868-1971
1997.0042
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
30.0 Linear feet
Payroll vouchers and correspondence pertaining to the Central New England Railway, the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad, and the Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad. Also includes public and employee timetables of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, western region.
Beaujon, Leroy Y. [Collector.]
History
The Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad was formed in 1881 from the remnants of the bankrupt Connecticut Western Railroad, which was formed in 1868 and ran from Hartford, Connecticut, into Litchfield County, Connecticut, and on to Pine Plains, New York. After 1881 the H&CW purchased the Rhinebeck & Connecticut Railroad to extend the line to Rhinecliff, New York. In 1889 the H&CW was absorbed into the Central New England & Western Railroad, which was created after a bridge was built over the Hudson River at Poughkeepsie, New York, to facilitate coal freight and passenger traffic from Pennsylvania and eastern New York into southern New England. In 1892 the CNE&WRR was purchased by the Philadelphia & Reading Railroad to become the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad.
In 1898 the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad became the Central New England Railway. In 1900 a branch line was formed from Tariffville, Connecticut, to Agawam Junction, Massachusetts. In 1904 the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad purchased control of the CNE in order to obtain the Poughkeepsie Bridge, but the CNE was operated as an independent company until it was totally absorbed by the NYNH&HRR in 1927.
Leroy Y. Beaujon was born in 1929 in Canaan, Connecticut, and worked for the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad from 1947 to 1957 (excepting the years he served in the U.S. Army from 1953 to 1956) in station and tower service. He started working in the travel industry in 1957 and moved to California in 1973, where he currently resides.
Scope and Content
The Leroy Y. Beaujon Railroad Collection consists of payroll vouchers and paychecks, correspondence, a scrapbook, and photographs related to the Central New England Railway ( CNE) and its predecessor companies, including the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad and the Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad. The Central New England Railway, which ran from eastern New York through western and parts of central Connecticut and into southern Massachusetts, was absorbed by the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in 1927. Also included is a scrapbook of newspaper clippings, documents, and photographs with information about the Housatonic Railroad and the Canaan, Connecticut, railroad station, which was the victim of arson in 2001. These materials were gathered by Mr. Beaujon, a historian of the railroad lines of western Connecticut.
The collection also includes 483 public timetables, from 1892 to 1968, from the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad of the western region of the system ("Lines West"), with one timetable, from 1969, of Penn Central, New Haven Division. Also includes are 143 employee timetables, from 1915 to 1969, of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad's western division, which included the former Central New England Railway lines.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to New England railroads. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Brock, John.; Administrative Records.; Central New England Railway Company.; Connecticut Western Railroad Company.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad.; New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad.; Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Railroad stations -- Connecticut.; Railroads--Massachusetts.; Railroads--New York.; Scrap-Books.; Timetables.
- Series I: Collection, undated, 1868-1971
  - Central New England Railway payroll vouchers, 1898-1903 (Box 1)
  - Central New England Railway payroll vouchers, 1899-1903 (Box 2)
  - Central New England Railway payroll vouchers, 1899-1902 (Box 3)
  - Central New England Railway correspondence, 1890-1902 (Box 4)
  - Central New England Railway correspondence, 1890-1902 (Box 5)
  - Central New England Railway correspondence, 1890-1902 (Box 6)
  - Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad payroll vouchers, 1893-1894 (Box 7)
  - Central New England Railway, Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad, Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad vouchers and correspondence, undated (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad and Central New England Railway payroll vouchers, 1893, 1901-1903 (Box 9)
  - Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad and Central New England Railway payroll vouchers, 1893-1989, 1901-1903 (Box 10)
  - Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad vouchers, 1893-1898 (Box 11)
  - Letters written to and from John Brock, president of the Central New England Railway and the earlier Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad and others. Many of the letters are from Baldwin Locomotive Works, 1890-1902 (Box 12)
  - Photographs and negatives, 1878-1971 (Box 13)
    General note
    Photographic negatives in the collection are primarily scenes of stations along CNE. The list is arranged by the number which appears on the sleeve for each negative. In some cases the same number has been made part of the negative itself. Additional information, sometimes penciled on the sleeve, is summarized in the column called "other". The rail line is given since some of the negatives pertain to geographic areas not under the umbrella of the CNE or one of its predecessor lines. Occasionally "New Haven" has been used interchangeably with "CNE" (see numbers 8047 and 8048 for example). In order to assure that information contained in this list matches the notations on the sleeves, no attempt has been made to revise conflicting comments.
    - Central New England Railway, Collinsville, Connecticut, original station, 1920s (Other Neg. 1)
    - Central New England Railway, Boston Corners, New York, from New York Central Railroad tracks looking north, 1923 (Other Neg. 3)
    - Central New England Railway, West Suffield, Connecticut, looking south, 1936 (Other Neg. 6)
    - Central New England Railway, Billings, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 7)
    - Central New England Railway, Canton, Connecticut, 1923 (Other Neg. 9)
    - Central New England Railway, Boston Corners, New York, Looking North, 1934 (Other Neg. 15)
    - Central New England Railway, Modena, New York, 1931 (Other Neg. 18)
    - Central New England Railway, Lawrence's, Connecticut, 1928 (Other Neg. 22)
    - Central New England Railway, West Winsted, Connecticut, (torn down, 1930), 1928 (Other Neg. 23)
    - Central New England Railway, Canton, Connecticut, looking east, 1930 June 22 (Other Neg. 24)
    - Central New England Railway, New Hartford, Connecticut, 1927 September 5 (Other Neg. 25)
    - Central New England Railway, Ancram, New York, looking west, 1933 October 12 (Other Neg. 30)
    - Central New England Railway, Copake, New York, 1927 September 26 (Other Neg. 54)
    - Central New England Railway, Cokertown, New York, undated (Other Neg. 61)
    - New Haven Railroad, Danbury, Connecticut, 1936 June (Other Neg. 71)
    - Central New England Railway, New Hartford, Connecticut, 1934 (Other Neg. 96)
    - Central New England Railway, New Hartford, Connecticut, 1908-1909 (Other Neg. 97)
    - Central New England Railway, Norfolk, Connecticut, old depot, 1878 (Other Neg. 98)
    - Central New England Railway, Hoskins, Connecticut, looking north and east, 1929 June 22 (Other Neg. 100)
    - Central New England Railway, Twin Lakes, Connecticut, 1930 June 23 (Other Neg. 101)
    - Central New England Railway, Copake, New York, 1927 September 6 (Other Neg. 102)
    - Central New England Railway, Pine Meadow, Connecticut, 1927 September 5 (Other Neg. 103)
    - Central New England Railway, Lead Mines, New York, 1927 September 6 (Other Neg. 104)
    - Central New England Railway, East Canaan, Connecticut, 1928 June 23 (Other Neg. 105)
    - Central New England Railway, Bloomfield, Connecticut, 1929 June 22 (Other Neg. 106)
    - Central New England Railway, Oak Summit, New York, 1-124 and 1-116 Negative, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 107)
    - Central New England Railway, Attlebury, New York, Carl Richter and Bob Adams in picture, 1932 April (Other Neg. 108)
    - Central New England Railway, Arthursburgh, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 111)
    - Central New England Railway, Summit, Connecticut, 1928 (Other Neg. 113)
    - Central New England Railway, Norfolk, Connecticut, 1933 (Other Neg. 114)
    - Central New England Railway, Stissing Junction, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 115)
    - Central New England Railway, Salisbury, Connecticut, 1930 June 23 (Other Neg. 116)
    - Central New England Railway, Taconic, Connecticut, 1930 June 23 (Other Neg. 117)
    - Central New England Railway, Ore Hill, Connecticut, 1928 June 28 (Other Neg. 118)
    - Central New England Railway, Brinckerhoff, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 119)
    - Central New England Railway, Barnards, Connecticut, 1936 (Other Neg. 120)
    - Central New England Railway, Clintondale, New York, in sleeve w/neg 121, 1931 April (Other Neg. 109)
    - Central New England Railway, Clintondale, New York, in sleeve w/neg 109, 1931 April (Other Neg. 121)
    - Central New England Railway, West Suffield, Connecticut, looking north; J. L. Stewart in photo, 1936 (Other Neg. 122)
    - Central New England Railway, Verbank, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 123)
    - Central New England Railway, Verbank Village, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 124)
    - Central New England Railway, Shekomeko, New York, 1-124 and 1-116 Negative, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 125a)
    - Central New England Railway, St. Elmo, New York, 1936 (Other Neg. 126)
    - Central New England Railway, Moore's Mills, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 131)
    - Central New England Railway, Mt. Riga, New York, "Joint Station" on the sleeve, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 132)
    - Central New England Railway, Fishkill Plains, New York, 1931 April (Other Neg. 133)
    - Central New England Railway, Glenham, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 134)
    - Central New England Railway, Fishkill, New York, 1931 April (Other Neg. 135)
    - Central New England Railway, East Granby, Connecticut, looking north, 1936 (Other Neg. 136)
    - Central New England Railway, East Walden, New York, " Bob Adams car by station", 1932 November (Other Neg. 137)
    - Central New England Railway, Feeding Hills, Massachusetts, looking toward Beacon, 1936 (Other Neg. 138)
    - Central New England Railway, Mattewan, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 140)
    - New Haven Railroad, Norwich, Connecticut, 1971 September 1 (Other Neg. 790)
    - New Haven Railroad, Moosup, Connecticut, 1971 September 1 (Other Neg. 825)
    - New Haven Railroad, Plainfield Junction, Connecticut, 1971 September 1 (Other Neg. 826)
    - New Haven Railroad, Broad Brook, Connecticut, 1933 October 12 (Other Neg. 923)
    - Central New England Railway, Griffins, Connecticut, 1933 October 12 (Other Neg. 925)
    - Central New England Railway, Arthursburgh, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 927)
    - New Haven Railroad, Hazardville, Connecticut, 1933 October 12 (Other Neg. 928)
    - Central New England Railway, Tariffville, Connecticut, 1936 (Other Neg. 929)
    - Central New England Railway, La Grange, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 965)
    - New Haven Railroad, Amston, New York, 1933 (Other Neg. 994)
    - Central New England Railway, Stissing Junction, New York, looking toward Beacon and Poughkeepsie, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 995)
    - New Haven Railroad, Norwich, Connecticut, 1931 November 11 (Other Neg. 998)
    - Central New England Railway, Pine Plains, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 8022)
    - New Haven Railroad, New Hartford, Connecticut, 1927 September 5 (Other Neg. 8044)
    - New Haven Railroad, New Hartford, Connecticut, 1934 (Other Neg. 8045)
    - Central New England Railway, Winsted, Connecticut, Bulletin Board, 1927 September 5 (Other Neg. 8046)
    - Central New England Railway, Collinsville, Connecticut, 1930 June 22 (Other Neg. 8047)
    - New Haven Railroad, Collinsville, Connecticut, 1930 June 22 (Other Neg. 8048)
    - Central New England Railway, West Suffield, Connecticut, 1930 June 22 (Other Neg. 8049)
    - Central New England Railway, Campbell Hall, New York, 1931 November (Other Neg. 8050)
    - Central New England Railway, Millerton, New York, 1938 (Other Neg. 8051)
    - Central New England Railway, Silvernails, New York, looking west, 1938 (Other Neg. 8057)
    - Central New England Railway, Wicopee Junction, New York, looking toward Beacon, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 8062)
    - Central New England Railway, Red Hook, New York, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9068)
    - Central New England Railway, Elizaville, New York, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9069)
    - Central New England Railway, Jackson Corners, New York, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9071)
    - Central New England Railway, Stanfordville, New York, looking north, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9074)
    - Central New England Railway, Pleasant Valley, New York, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9075)
    - Central New England Railway, Poughkeepsie Bridge, looking east From Highland, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9078)
    - Central New England Railway, Poughkeepsie, New York, old Poughkeepsie & Eastern Railroad station, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9081)
    - Central New England Railway, Poughkeepsie, New York, old Poughkeepsie & Eastern Railroad station, 1970 June 1 (Other Neg. 9082)
    - Central New England Railway, Stormville, New York, from postcard, undated (Other Neg. 9426)
    - Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad, Lakeville, Connecticut(?), snow train, 1895 (Other Neg. 9475)
    - Central Vermont Railway, Orcutts, Connecticut, 1933 October 12 (Other Neg. 9674)
    - New Haven Railroad, Colchester, Connecticut, 1933 (Other Neg. 9846)
    - New Haven Railroad -- Airline Division, East Hampton, Connecticut, undated (Other Neg. 9849)
    - New Haven Railroad, Hawleyville, Connecticut, 1936 (Other Neg. 9850)
    - New Haven Railroad, Windsor, Connecticut, 1933 October 12 (Other Neg. 9861)
    - Central New England Railway, Wicopee, Junction, New York, 1932 November 5 (Other Neg. 9427)
    - New Haven Railroad, Suffield, Connecticut ?, 1936 (Other Neg. 9851)
    - New Haven Railroad, Plantsville, Connecticut, 1935 (Other Neg. 9854)
    - New Haven Railroad, Portland, Connecticut, 1936 (Other Neg. 9855)
    - New Haven Railroad, Suffield, Connecticut, 1933 October 12 (Other Neg. 9857)
    - Envelope containing single negatives with multiple images, 1890s (Other Envelope 1997-1)
      - Top - CNE combo coach/baggage, Canaan, Connecticut, 1890s
      - Bottom - truss bridge over Blackberry River, Canaan, Connecticut, 1890s
    - Envelope containing single negatives with multiple images, 1890s (Other Envelope 1997-2)
      - Top - Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad steam shovel, 1890s
      - Bottom - Central New England Railway combo coach/baggage RPO #71, 1890s
    - Envelope containing single negatives with multiple images, undated (Other Envelope 1997-3)
      - Upper Left - Central New England Railway milk car #94 interior, undated
      - Lower left- Central New England Railway milk car #94 exterior side, undated
      - Lower right- Central New England Railway milk car #94 end, undated
      - Upper right - CNE combo/baggage car #64, undated
  - Letter to John Brock, President of the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad, from E. C. M. Rand of the Poughkeepsie & Eastern Railway, March 1, 1898. Rand asks Brock if he will let him know the status of the reorganization of the Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad; Rand wishes to connect to the line when it is reorganized (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Western Railroad, two items: " Connecticut Western Railroad, its feasibility and importance to Hartford," printed in 1868 (photocopy); "An Act Incorporating the Connecticut Western Railroad Company," (photocopy) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Hartford & Connecticut Western Railroad, three items: May 7, 1885, letter to J. F. Jones, Superintendent, from D. R. Sullivan, about a switch that hadn't been moved and prevented a Newburgh, Dutchess & Connecticut Railroad train to move; "Sixth Annual Report of the President and Directors of the Hartford & Connecticut Western Railroad to the Stockholders to be submitted at their Annual Meeting in the City of Hartford, on Tuesday, December 10, 1887," (typescript copy); "Statement of Facts by the Hartford & Connecticut Western R.R. Co. in support of their Petition for Charter to Extend their Road to Springfield," (typescript), undated, 1885, 1887 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Paychecks to Central New England Railway employees and photographs of CNE scenes, stations and locomotives, 1880-1910 (Box 15)
  - Large album/scrapbook of historical documents, photos, newspaper clippings, etc. related to the Housatonic Railroad and the Canaan, Connecticut, Union Station (including station floor plans from 1948), undated, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Large album/scrapbook of copies of historical documents and information about the Connecticut Western Railroad and the Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad, undated (Box 17)
  - Large album/scrapbook of copies of historical documents and information about the Central New England and Western Railroad, undated (Box 18)
  - Timetables, 1892-1969
    - Public timetables of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, 1892-1969
      - 1892-1917 (Box 19)
      - 1918-1926 (Box 20)
      - 1927-1930 (Box 21)
      - 1931-1933 (Box 22)
      - 1934-1940 (Box 23)
      - 1941-1949 (Box 24)
      - [note that the 1969 timetable is from Penn Central], 1950-1969 (Box 25)
    - Employee timetables of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, Western Division, 1915-1969
      - 1915-1922 (Box 26)
      - 1922-1927 (Box 27)
      - 1927-1932 (Box 28)
      - 1933-1940 (Box 29)
      - 1940-1946 (Box 30)
      - 1947-1953 (Box 31)
      - 1954-1961 (Box 32)
      - 1962-1969 (Box 33)